A Finding Aid to the William Chapin Seitz Papers, circa 1930-1995, in the Archives of American Art AAA.seitwill
Archives of American Art
- Research and Writing Files, 1940s-1970s; Series 4; 23.5 Linear feet Boxes 4-26
  - People and Subject Files, 1940s-1970s; 4.2
    - Drugs, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Duchamp, Marcel, 1960s; 2 Folders (Box 8, Folder 37-38)
      (Includes transcript of interview)
    - Earthworks, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Ecological, Mineral Art, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Education, 1960s-1970s (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Egbert, Donald, 1960s (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Engineering, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - England, 1965-1971 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Enviornment, 1960s-1970s (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Enviornmental Art, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Enviornmental Crisis, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Enviornments, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Enviornments, Urban, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Ethics, 1964-1971 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Europe vs. America, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Exhibition Technology, 1950s (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Expressionism, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Fakes, 1963-1973 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Fashion, 1967-1971 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Figure, 1963-1970 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Figure Symposium and Show, 1962; 2 Folders (Box 9, Folder 19-20)
    - Film, 1960s-1970s (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Flag, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Formalist Art, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Freedom of Artists, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Friends of Peter Bent Brigham Hospital, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Friends of the Whitney Museum of American Art, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Future, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Futurism, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Galleries, 1970-1973 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Galleries, Europe, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Gallery Maps, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Games, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Gatch, Lee, 1940s-1960s (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Geldzahler, Henry, 1960s-1970s (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Gorky, Arshile, 1950s (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Gottlieb, Adolph, 1940s-1960s (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Graphics, 1966-1973 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Graves, Morris, 1940s (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Greece Trip, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Greenberg, Clement, 1940s-1960s (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Group Shows, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Guggenheim, 1964-1970 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Guston, Phillip, 1950s-1960s (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Happenings, 1960s; 2 Folders (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Hard Edge Painting and Sculpture, 1970s (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Heller, Ben and Mrs., 1950s-1960s (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Hess, Thomas B., 1950s (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Hilles Collection, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Hirshhorn, Joe, 1960s-1970s (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - History, 1970s (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Hoffmann, Hans, 1960s; 3 Folders (Box 10, Folder 9-11)
    - Homosexuality, 1966-1970s (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Huxtable, Ada Louise, 1970s (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Ideas, 1950s; 4 Folders (Box 10, Folder 14-17)
    - Illustrations and Articles, circa 1966 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Impressionism, Art News, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Impressionsm, Relevance of, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Impressionism, National Gallery Exhibition, early 1970s (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Information Fallout, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Installation, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Intellectual, Role of, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Irony and Humor, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Israeli Art, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Italian Paintings, Central, 1950s (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Japan, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Jokes, Art, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Kandinsky, Wassily, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Kaprow, Alan, 1960s (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Kassel, Germany, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Kinetic Art, 1955-1960s (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Kirchner, Ernst Ludwig, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Kitsun, 1960s-1970s (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Klee, Paul, 1940s-1950s (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Knaths, Karl, circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Kootz, Sam, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Kramer, Hilton, 1960s-1970s (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Krebs, Rockne, 1960s-1970s; 2 Folders (Box 10, Folder 40-41)
    - Landscape, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Las Vegas, Nevada, 1960s (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Leftist Theory, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Left, New Left, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Light, 1965-1970 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Linder, Richard, 1960s (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Literature, 1953-1971 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - London, England, 1960s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - London Art, 1963-1972 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Magritte, Rene, 1960s-1970s; 2 Folders (Box 11, Folder 10-11)
    - Manifestos, 1940s-1960s (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Martin, Anthony, 1970s (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Marcuse, Herbert, 1970s (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Matisse, Henri, 1960s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Matta, Roberto Echaurren, 1950s-1960s (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - McLuhan, Marshall, 1960s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Multimedia, 1960s-1971; 3 Folders (Box 11, Folder 18-20)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1970-1973 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Mexico, circa 1969 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Miro, Joan, 1970s (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Modernism, 1970-1972; 2 Folders (Box 11, Folder 24-25)
    - Modigliani, Amedeo, 1960s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Mondarian, Piet, 1960s-1972; 2 Folders (Box 11, Folder 27-28)
    - Monet, Claude, 1950s-1960s; 4 Folders (Box 11, Folder 29-32)
    - Monet, Claude, 1950s-1960s; 19 Folders (Box 12, Folder 1-19)
    - Motherwell, Robert, 1950s-1970s; 2 Folders (Box 12, Folder 20-21)
    - Munson, Paul, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Multiples, 1968-1971 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Murals, circa 1968-1973 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Museum of Modern Art, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Museums, Universities, 1970s (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Museums, 1960s-1970s; 6 Folders (Box 13, Folder 6-11)
    - Music, Criticism and History, 1950s-1970s (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Music and Film, 1960s-1970s; 2 Folders (Box 13, Folder 13-14)
    - Nalota, Louise, 1960s (Box 13, Folder 15)
      (Tap City Circus)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, 1970s (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - National Gallery of Art, 1970s (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - National Shopping Centers, Inc., 1960s-1970s (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - National Styles, 1960s-1974 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Nature and Nature Painters, 1948-1970s (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Neo-Humanists, 1960s (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Nevada, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - New York, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - New York, Artists, 1960s-1970s (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - New York, Herald Tribune, 1961-1962 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - New York, Scene, 1960-1971 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - New York, Downtown, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Newman, Barnett, 1969-1970 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Nixon, Richard, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - O'Doherty, Brian, 1970s (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Obituaries, 1966-1974 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Opposites, 1960s (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Optical Art, Theory, 1960s; 3 Folders (Box 14, Folder 4-6)
    - Orient, 1950s-1970s (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Oster, Jerry, 1960s (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Painting, Americna, 1960s (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Panels, 1962-1968 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Paris, Paris Galleries, 1950s-1973 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - People, Personalities, 1954-1972 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Perception, 1970s (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Periodicals, Art, 1970s (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Personnel, Literature and Art, 1960s (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Philosophy, 1970s (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Photos of Artists and Paintings, 1951-1974; 2 Folders (Box 14, Folder 17-19)
    - Picasso and Dewey, 1974 May; 2 Folders (Box 14, Folder 20-21)
    - Picasso, Pablo, 1940s-1970s (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Pictorial Means, 1940s-1950s (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1967-1970 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Plastic, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Poetry, 1962-1970 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Politics, 1970s; 2 Folders (Box 14, Folder 27-28)
    - Pollock, Jackson, 1950s-1970s (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Pop, 1960s-1970s (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Pop, 1960s-1970s; 2 Folders (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
    - Pornography, 1960s-1970s (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Portraiture, Modern, 1967-1971 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Posters, 1970s (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Pousette-Dart, Richard, 1970s (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Primitive Art, 1960s-1970s (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Princeton University, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Protests, 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Psychedelic Data, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Psychology of Art, 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Psychology, Abnormal, 1970s; 1946; 2 Folders (Box 15, Folder 12-13)
    - Public Relation Data, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Publishers, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Purists, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Quality in Sculpture, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Radical Realist Painters, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Realism, 1970-1973 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Regional Styles, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Reich, Charles, 1970s (Box 15, Folder 21)
      (The Greening of America)
    - Relevance, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Religion, Art, 1950-1972 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Renwick Gallery, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Resnick, Milton, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Researchers, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Responsive Eye, 1968-1971 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Retirement, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Revolution, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Rhode Island School of Design, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Rock, etc., 1970-1973 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Romanticism in 20th Century Art, 1950s (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Rome, Italy, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Rosati, James, 1960s-1970s (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Rosenberg, Harold, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Rothko, Mark, 1953-1970s; 2 Folders (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    - Russia, 1960s-1970s (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Sao Paolo Preview Dinner, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Schwitters, Kurt, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Science Art, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Scientific American, 1960s (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Schull, Robert, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Sculpture Symposium, 1952 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Sculpture, Monumental, 1968-1972; 2 Folders (Box 16, Folder 10-11)
    - Segal, George, 1971-1972; 4 Folders (Box 16, Folder 12-15)
    - Selz, Peter and Thalia, 1960-1973 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Sensibility, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Seventies, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Sewall, John Ives, 1952-1960 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Shahn, Ben, 1949-1952 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Shapiro, Meyer, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Singer Building, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Sixties Record, 1960s-1970s (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Smith, Leon, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Smith, Tony, 1967-1971 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Sociology and Anthropology, 1960s-1970s (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Soho, 1971-1973 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Spaces, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Spoerri, Daniel, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Steefel, Pete, 1960s (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Stella, Frank, 1960s (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Still, Clyfford, 1960s (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Stuyvesant Collection, 1960s (Box 16, Folder 33)
      (Kinetic Art)
    - Styles, 1960s (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - SUNY Exhibition, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Surrealism, 1960s-1970s (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Sutherland, Graham, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Symbolism, 1970-1972 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Tamarind Lithography Workshop, 1960s; 2 Folders (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
    - Taste, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Taylor-Page, 1960s (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Technology, 1960s-1970s; 2 Folders (Box 17, Folder 7-8)
    - TV, 1970s (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Theater, 1970s (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Theme Exhibitions, 1960s-1970s (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Tinguely, Jean, 1960s (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Toronto, Canada, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Toulouse-Lautrec, Henri de, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Tobey, Mark, 1960s; 11 Folders (Box 17, Folder 15-25)
      (Includes transcripts of interviews)
    - University of Washington, Seattle, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - University of Virginia, 1960s (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Venice, Italy, 1960s-1970s (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Video Art, 1963-1970 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Virginia, 1970s (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Virginia, Museums, 1972-1973 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Virginia Biennial, 1971-1973; 2 Folders (Box 17, Folder 32-33)
    - Vocabulary, 1970s (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - Warhol, Andy, 1967-1971 (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - Washington Artists, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - Washington, D.C., 1971 (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - Wasserman, Max and Jeanne, 1960s (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - Watts Tower, 1961-1965 (Box 17, Folder 39)
    - Willard, Marian, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 40)
    - Women Artists, 1970-1972; 2 Folders (Box 17, Folder 41-42)
    - Youth, 1970s (Box 17, Folder 43)
    - General Painting and Sculpture, 1950s-1970s; 16 Folders (Box 18, Folder 1-16)
  - Thesis Writings and Research, 1950s; 4.3
    This subseries contains drafts, research materials, correspondence, exams, proposals, and outlines concerning William Seitz's thesis.
    - Thesis Materials, 1950s; 22 Folders (Box 19, Folder 1-22)
  - General Research, 1950s-1970s; 4.4
    This subseries contains lecture materials, writings and drafts of writings, book reviews, notes, bibliographies, and materials from binders kept by Seitz on various subjects.
    - Lecture Files, 1960s; 20 Folders (Box 20, Folder 1-20)
      Postwar Style
      Mark Tobey
      Virginia Biennial
      The Artist: Prophet or Victim?
      The Artist and the Innovative Crisis
      Rene D'Harnoncourt Eulogy
      Princeton University Alumni
      Seasons and Moments
    - Art in the Age of Aquarius, 1974; 5 Folders (Box 20, Folder 21-25)
    - Concerning Monet, 1967 March (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Poem about the Castelli Gallery, 1967 February (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Pictorial Arts, 1950s; 4 Folders (Box 20, Folder 28-31)
    - Books Reviews by Seitz, 1960s-1970s (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Books Reviews not by Seitz, 1960s-1970s (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - "Part 1, Chapter 1,", 1973 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - Relevance of Impressionism, 1960s (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - Mondrian and Relationships, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Materials for Modernist Book, 1970s; 8 Folders (Box 20, Folder 37-44)
    - Materials for Modernist Book, 1970s; 3 Folders (Box 21, Folder 1-3)
    - Resnick Paints a Picture, by Lawrence Campbell, 1960s (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Problems of New Directions Exhibitions, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Impressionism, circa 1969; 2 Folders (Box 21, Folder 6-7)
    - Introduction for Canadian Symposium, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Modern Art, 1951-1967; 3 Folders (Box 21, Folder 9-11)
    - Matisse and the Fauves, 1960s (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Psychological and Social Reasons in Contemporary Art, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Bibliography, 1950s-1970s; 9 Folders (Box 21, Folder 14-22)
    - Italian Paintings, 1950s; 4 Folders (Box 21, Folder 23-26)
    - 8x5 Index Cards, Notes, 1950s (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Binders, 1950s-1960s; 17 Folders (Box 22, Folder 1-17)
      Subjects include:
      Prints
      Monet
      "Shelf Book"
      "Articles"
      Tables and Charts
      Painting Bibliography
    - General Notes, circa 1935-1960s; 14 Folders (Box 22, Folder 18-31)
    - General Notes, circa 1935-1960s; 4 Folders (Box 23, Folder 1-4)
  - Card Files, circa 1940s-1960s; 4.5
    This subseries contains five boxes of index cards used by William Chapin Seitz to organize references to works of art, artists, subjects, movements, locations, and bibliographic references.
    - Card Files, 1940s-1960s (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Card Files, 1940s-1960s; 4 Folders (Box 24, Folder 1-4)
  - Interview and Lecture Sound Recordings, 1960s-1970s; 4.6
    This subseries contains 30 recordings of lectures, interviews, and music on sound tape reels (1/4 in. tape) and sound cassettes. Labels for lectures have been taken from the boxes in which the reels were housed, and have not been verified. Recordings have not been digitized and use of materials requires advanced notice.
    - Artist: Prophet or Victim?, 1969 March 13; 3 sound tape reels (Box 25, Item 1-3)
    - Fine Arts Lecture Series, Aspects of Romanticism, 1961; 1 sound tape reels (Box 25, Item 4)
    - The Rise and Dissolution of the Avant Garde, circa 1960s; 1 sound tape reels (Box 25, Item 5)
    - Unknown, Unlabeled, circa 1960s; 1 sound tape reels (Box 25, Item 6)
    - The Counter Avant Garde, Clement Greenberg, 1970 May 13; 1 sound tape reels (Box 25, Item 7)
    - Lessons in French, Music, 1960s; 1 sound tape reels (Box 25, Item 8)
    - Art Symposium, 1968 March 4; 1 sound tape reels (Box 25, Item 9)
    - ERN(?), Lecture at Brandeis University, 1969 March 13; 1 sound tape reels (Box 25, Item 10)
    - ERN, Panel Discussion, Gorky, 1962 December 20; 1 sound tape reels (Box 25, Item 11)
    - Bruce Glaser Inverview, with Lawrence Alloway and William Chapin Seitz, 1966 June 15; 1 sound tape reels (Box 25, Item 12)
    - Music, 1960s; 3 sound tape reels (Box 25, Item 13-15)
    - Music, 1962; 1 sound tape reels (Box 26, Item 1)
    - Gorky, 1962; 1 sound tape reels (Box 26, Item 2)
    - William Chapin Seitz, Albers, Criticism Symposium, 1960s; 1 sound tape reels (Box 26, Item 3)
    - The Art World, James Rosati, 1969 November 30; 1 sound tape reels (Box 26, Item 4)
    - Milton Resnick with John Lloyd Taylor, 1972 July 25- August 20; 3 sound tape reels (Box 26, Item 5-7)
    - Segal, 1971 January 21; 3 Sound cassettes (Box 26, Item 8-10)
    - Jean Wasserman, 1966 August; 1 sound tape reels (Box 26, Item 11)
    - Criticism Symposium, 1960s; 1 sound tape reels (Box 26, Item 12)
    - William Chapin Seitz on Radio and TV, 1960s; 1 sound tape reels (Box 26, Item 13)
    - ATFL, 1960s January 22; 1 sound tape reels (Box 26, Item 14)
    - Rosati Discussion, 1969 May; 1 sound tape reels (Box 26, Item 15)
    - Artist, 1969; 1 sound tape reels (Box 26, Item 1)
    - Artist, 1969; 1 sound tape reels (Box 26, Item 1)
- Teaching Files, circa 1945-1970s; Series 5; 4.9 Linear feet Boxes 27-31, OV 34-35
  This series is comprised of lecture notes, outlines and class materials used by Seitz while teaching at the University of Buffalo, the Univeristy of Virginia, Brandeis University, and for a seminar on Robert Motherwell at Oberlin College; a copy of a thesis written by William C. Agee while at Princeton University; course number specific binders of notes that do not reference any particular school; and subject specific binders of notes that were likely used as reference materials for teaching.
  - University Specific Teaching Files, 1960s-1970s; 24 Folders (Box 27, Folder 1-24)
    University of Buffalo
    Brandeis University
    University of Virginia
    Princeton University
    Oberlin College
  - Course Number Specific Teaching Files, circa 1949-1960s; 24 Folders (Box 28, Folder 1-24)
  - Course Number Specific Teaching Files, circa 1949-1960s; 12 Folders (Box 29, Folder 1-12)
  - Reference Files (Box 29)
    - Carolingian Art, circa 1950s (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - St. Denis Bible, circa 1950s; 2 Folders (Box 29, Folder 14-15)
    - Illuminated Manuscripts, circa 1950s; 2 Folders (Box 29, Folder 16-17)
    - Early Christian Iconography, circa 1950s; 2 Folders (Box 29, Folder 18-19)
    - Chinese Figure Style and Art, circa 1950s; 3 Folders (Box 29, Folder 20-22)
  - Reference Files (Box 30)
    - Chinese Landscape, circa 1945-1950s; 2 Folders (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
    - Nativity, circa 1945-1950s; 3 Folders (Box 30, Folder 3-5)
    - Byzantine Art, circa 1945-1950s (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Mimeographed Readings, circa 1945-1950s (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Modern Architecture, circa 1945-1950s; 2 Folders (Box 30, Folder 8-9)
    - Modern Paintings, circa 1945-1950s; 2 Folders (Box 30, Folder 10-11)
    - Modern and Renaissance Sculpture, circa 1945-1950s; 5 Folders (Box 30, Folder 12-16)
    - Transition and Gothic Architecture, circa 1945-1950s (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Byzantine and Eastern Medieval Architecture, circa 1945-1950s; 2 Folders (Box 30, Folder 18-19)
  - Reference Files (Box 31)
    - Renaissance Sculpture, circa 1945-1950s (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Northern Renaissance Sculpture, circa 1945-1950s; 2 Folders (Box 31, Folder 2-3)
    - Art 401, circa 1945-1950s; 2 Folders (Box 31, Folder 4-5)
    - Flemish Painting, circa 1945-1950s (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Early French and Spanish Painting, circa 1945-1950s (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Aesthetics, circa 1945-1950s (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Renaissance, circa 1945-1950s; 2 Folders (Box 31, Folder 9-10)
    - Roman Architecture, circa 1945-1950s; 2 Folders (Box 31, Folder 11-12)
    - Renaissance, circa 1945-1950s; 2 Folders (Box 31, Folder 13-14)
    - General, circa 1945-1950s; 8 Folders (Box 31, Folder 15-22)
      Oversized material housed in OV 34 and OV 35
    - Oversized General, Chronologies, circa 1945-1950s (Box OV 34)
      Oversized material from Box 31, F15
    - Oversized General, Chronologies, circa 1945-1950s (Box OV 35)
- Printed Material, 1937-1984; Series 6; 0.5 Linear feet Box 31-32
  This scattered series consists of articles, clippings, reproductions of works of art and exhibition materials concerning or by Seitz.
  - "Quality in Sculpture", Baltimore Museum of Art Announcement, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Written by Seitz, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Clippings, by or about Seitz, 1950s-1960s (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Clippings, with Writings by Seitz, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, with Seitz as Consultant, 1960s (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - "The Real and the Artificial,", 1973 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, with Illustrations by Seitz, 1937; undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, Seitz's Works of Art, 1949-1950s; 1975; 2 Folders (Box 32, Folder 5-6)
  - Britannica Entry for Monet, by Seitz, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Reproductions of Works of Art by Seitz, 1930s; 1950s (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - New York Times Clippings, 1937 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1961-1979 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Frank Stella Profile, 1984 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1950s-1970s; 8 Folders (Box 32, Folder 12-19)
  - Miscellaneous, 1950s-1977; 3 Folders (Box 32, Folder 20-22)
- Photographs, 1940s-1981; Series 7; 11 Folders Box 32, 33
  This series consists of scattered photographs of Seitz with others, likely friends and colleagues; photographs of installations of works of art at the University of Virginia exhibition for Seitz; works of art by William Seitz, Irma Seitz, and others (likely works owned by Seitz).
  - Photos of Seitz with Others, 1940s-1960s (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Photos by and of Others, 1960s; 3 Folders (Box 32, Folder 24)
    Oversized photos housed in Box 33
  - Photos of Installations at UVA, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - Photos of Works of Art, Donated to Princeton University, 1960s (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - Photos of Works of Art, by Seitz, 1940s-1960s; 3 Folders (Box 32, Folder 27-29)
  - Photos of Works of Art, by Irma Seitz, 1960s; 2 Folders (Box 32, Folder 30-31)
  - Photos of Works of Art, by Others, 1960s (Box 32, Folder 32)
  - Slides, 1960s (Box 32, Folder 33)
- Artwork, circa 1950s-1972; Series 8; 6 Folders Box 32, 33
  This series consists of sketches probably by Seitz, two works by Ellen Banks-Woodson, and one pencil sketch by Phil Elliott.
  - William Chapin Seitz, Pencil Sketches on Newsprint and Painting, circa 1950s (Box 32, Folder 34)
    Oversized painting housed in Box 33
  - Ellen Banks-Woodson, Oil on Canvas Sketch, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 35)
  - Ellen Banks-Woodson, Pencil on Paper Sketch, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 36)